# ALEX SHEPHARD

IT SUPPORT

3198305414 ashep50624@gmail.com Waterloo, IA www.linkedin.com/in/alex-shephard-3878a0301/

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I've recently acquired my Course Careers certification and am currently working on CompTIA A+. I have a desire to grow into a cybersecurity role as I continue to advance my education. I have plans to work on the Security+ and Networking+ certifications before moving on to something like the CCNA. I have a good baseline understanding of Linux distributions, experience with Azure and setting up an active directory, and am highly competent with computer hardware. I have lots of experience building and reselling gaming and home computers as well as setting up my personal home network. For a more detailed outline of my experience please refer to my website linked here: https://ashep1337.github.io/shephards.llc/

# FORMAL EDUCATION

CEDAR FALLS HIGH SCHOOL | Cedar Falls, IA

January 2008 - January 2012

## IT SUPPORT

CourseCareers is an in-depth online program that covers several areas of entry-level IT while deeply exploring those topics with hands-on labs. I have gained notable experience in setting up and configuring a help desk ticketing system (osTicket) from scratch, working with Microsoft Azure to create sandbox environments, configuring cloud-based firewalls (network security groups), setting up and configuring Active Directory, working with DNS, as well as working with file shares and permissions.

Some of the skills I learned through this rigorous program include: IT Support Basics, Networking Basics, Operating Systems and Cloud Fundamentals.

To view my full profile go to profile.coursecareers.com/alex.shephard

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### SOLE-PROPRIETOR | Shephard's L.L.C., Waterloo, IA

April 2019 - Present

- · Managing all aspects of rental properties.
- All repairs and updates.
- · Finding and replacing tenants.
- Self-employment
- · Learning trade skills like drywall, plumbing, and HVAC
- Advancing soft skills and learning how to remain professional when a tenant is not particularly kind.

# FOOD DIRECTOR | Bremer County Jail, Waverly, IA

February 2015 - March 2016

- · Maintain all kitchen activities and preparation of all meals for customers.
- · Hiring and firing employees.
- Creating schedules and food orders.
- · Setting a record low food cost while maintaining excellent food quality.
- Garnering a strong relationship with clients.
- · Fostering an efficient environment that reduces waste and excess labor.

- · Building new computers from used hardware.
- · Installing operating systems.
- · Ensuring customer satisfaction.
- · Sourcing inexpensive and quality parts from online and auctions.
- · Never having a returned PC or any broken parts during the building process.
- Learning about troubleshooting and software to determine health of hardware (like SMART data)

#### PORTFOLIO PROJECTS

#### MY WEBSITE

I thought it would be best to build a website that outlined and showcased my IT skills and also served as a portfolio and resume. I built this to have a more extensive and professional outline of projects and the history of my work and I am adding to it often.

Some goals I set out to achieve were:

- -Developing and editing HTML code
- -Deploying a live webpage that can be visited anywhere
- -Having access to a resume I can pull up with the search of an address.

I plan on buying a domain name and setting it to point at my website and also my mail for a proper professional feel.

https://ashep1337.github.io/shephards.llc/

#### LINUX DEPLOYMENT

This is a tutorial I made on how to install Linux Mint to a new environment. This includes verifying the files to make sure they are not infected or corrupted in any way.

Skills showcased:

- -Linux
- -BIOS
- -Installation on to boot drive
- -Sha256 encryption

https://github.com/ashep1337/linux-deployment

#### GITHUB PAGE

Projects outlined are osTicket, Azure Active Directory, and Linux deployment/SSH. I will continue to add more projects in the coming weeks.

A goal I had when creating this was to have a solid foundation of projects that I could later add to that outline my strengths in the IT field. I have achieved this by creating an organized readme file that I can add to and edit as I add projects to the list. This makes adding to my portfolio easier and allows me more time to focus on real-world projects

https://github.com/ashep1337/ashep1337

## ADDITIONAL EDUCATION

COMPTIA June 2024

CompTIA A+

Currently working on CompTIA A+ certification